OMAR SADEK

161 Roebling Street, Brooklyn, New York 11211(848) 468-2404 ◆ ⋈ omar.ysadek@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Experienced Full stack developer specializing in Java8, PHP7 and JavaScript with ten years of experience and strong debugging and problem-solving abilities and interpersonal skills. Accomplished in development and design, setting up and maintaining websites and applications, using various technologies. Possess strong leadership skills in a developer group. Involved in gathering user requirements, system analysis, design, development, testing and implementation. Excellent understanding of system development methodologies, techniques and tools. Exceptional ability to quickly master new concepts and capable of working ingroup as well as independently with excellent communication skills.

TECHNICAL EXPERTISE

Java8(SpringBoot)/PHP7(Symfony)
AWS/Azure

DevOps (Docker/Vagrant) Web Service REST JSON JavaScript(Angular, JQuery) Encryption/Decryption Git/Git-Flow

Continuous integration(Jenkins)

SQL(MySql)/MongoDB/Lucene Distributed cloud computing Agile Methodologies

Linux/MAC

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Datamarx - New York | Senior backend engineer

OCT 2018 - APR 2020

- Designed and developed a cutting edge proprietary authorization and multi factor authentication system using Java 8 with Spring Boot framework that encrypt/decrypt user information's.
- Developed a system for capturing real time browser extension events that scale up to MM/S back by AWS Lambda and SQS.
- Let the development of high scalable micro service that powered a real time smart ad recommendation system, also created an official technical specs for third party clients and internal web/engineering team.
- Worked very closely with leader technical ship to set technology standard and development practices.
- Led the development of dockerizing of our exciting stack.
- Architect and developed a PII service using Stanford CoreNLP to redact sensitive information.
- One of the lead developers that created the forms proprietary programmatic data collection unit for running an extremely accurate campaigns, main merge performance improvements by upgrading to PHP7 and ensure product stability by achieving greater than ~ 80% coverage.

Guidepoint Global - New York | PHP Developer

OCT 2017 - OCT 2018

 Software development using PHP5 (Symfony2) / MMSQL. Migrating to micro services (Lumen/Kong/Docker)

GRDF – Paris, France | PHP5 / Symfony2 Developer

JUN 2014 - JUN 2017

- Handled the realization of turnkey product solutions within IT systems director of GRDF, and in close proximity to the business through Scrum method.
- Led the management of 7 different projects with a team of 3 to 8 developers. Projects were completed between 4 and 16 months.

Projects

- Development of the tool Avenir ATHENA (emergency management tool for gas safety), OSS gas tool (tool
 for internal and external use, which simplifies and controls the sale of GrDF accompanying solutions), and
 "Carte de France des Références" tool (tool that allows to display on a map of France the references of the
 Markets)
- **Technologies:** Symfony2, AngularJS, Twig, Javascript, jQuery/UI, Node.js, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Redis, REST APIs, SOAP, MySQL, Google maps
- Tools: Git/Git-Flow, Docker, Vagrant, Jenkins, JIRA, Kanban
- Unit tests: PHPUnit
- Functional tests: Behat, Cucumber

Catholic Institute of Paris (ICP) – Paris, France | Software Developer

- **APR 2011 JUN 2014**
- Developed a web service under restful Symfony2 that powers a mobile application (ICP CAMPUS).
- Led the initiative of University online portal: port of Joomla 1.5 to 3, corrective maintenance and development of new features.
- Designed Resumes Library (Hal of ICP) using the Twig template.
- Developed modern and intuitive graphical interface in PHP and jQuery UI to simplify work of planning service for room's bookings.
- Implemented BI in Mondrian (Pentaho) / Saiku, an ETL script and several trigger in MySQL to have statistics in real time on room's occupancy rates.
- Developed Java script to control a Firefox PLC (SeleniumHQ) following scenarios. The goal is to detect in real time software malfunction of various online services we offer.

Netserve – Paris, France | Software Developer

FEB 2010 - MAR 2011

- Created and modified of various websites in PHP.
- Developed a network management software in Ruby on Rails.
- Developed in C of an embarked system connected to a Linux server via a serial connection (RS232), which plays the role of a home automation system.

EDUCATION

Ingésup – Paris, France Master Eurotech (Expert in Computer and Information Systems, equivalent to Master's Degree)	2012
Infosup - Paris, France BTS IRIS (Computing and Networking for Industry and Technical Services, equivalent to Associate Degree)	2009
Lycée KSA – Paris, France Bachelor of Science	2006

LANGUAGES

French | English | Arabic